Guide to the Guinea Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Guinea collection
1959-1998
MS 1520
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.27
(5 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to the political, economic, and social conditions in Guinea.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection, MS 605; Pamphlet Collection, MS 1351; African Postcard Collection, MS 1575. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to the political, economic, and social conditions in Guinea.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Women -- Guinea; Guinea -- Description and travel; Guinea -- Economic conditions; Guinea -- Politics and government; Guinea -- Social conditions; Mouvement national démocratique (Guinea)
- Inventory, 1959-1993
  - Government documents; journals; reports, 1959-1993, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Political organizations: journals; printed material, 1960-1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Guinée Actualités: journal, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - De l'Histoire du Parti Démocratique de Guinée, de la Conquête, de l'Exercice et du Développement du Pouvoir, by Ahmed Sekou Toure, Président de la Séminaire de Formation Idéologique, 1975 August 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Feminism/women's rights: journals; newsletters; printed material, 1977-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Le Combat: journal of l'Organisation Unifiée pour la Libération de la Guinée (l'OULG), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Guinea Investment Forum, Chase Manhattan Bank: printed material, 1982 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mouvement National Démocratique (MND): printed material, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General information pamphlets; brochures; booklets, 1986 November (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs: letter, 1990 March 30 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Investment and economic development reports, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Revolutionary People's Republic of Guinea, Ministry of Industry: memoranda, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Additional Material, 1985-1996; Accession 1995-M-177
  - Additional printed materials, 1985-1996, undated (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1960-1994; Accession 2006-M-036
  - Agence Guinéenne de Presse, Bulletin Spécial, 1960 October 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Les Aventures de Mambi, no. 1, 1985 May (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fonikee, Jeunesse de la Révolution Démocratique Africaine (J.R.D.A.), 1978, 1981 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - La Guinéenne, no. 1, 1986 March (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Guinéens pour la Démocratie Nouvelle, Cahiers de G.D.N., no. 2, 1979 May (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - La Nouvelle Ecole, no. 1, 1985 November-December (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - République de Guinée, Secrétariat d'État a la Recherche Scientifique, Recherches Africaines Bulleti n, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Samba, Album-Comique, no. 1, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - La Voie, no. 005, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Additional Material, 1987-1988, 1994, undated; Accession 2010-M-107
  Arrangement
  The material is arranged as received.
  - Genealogical tree of the messenger and saint prophets, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    In Maninka Nko script. (Kela Moo Lu Ni Nabinyima Lu Sun Yiri) One page.
  - Horoya Magazine, 1987 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Le Lanx: Hebdomadaire Satirique Indépendant, 1994 August 16, 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lettres Guinéennes, 1988 January-March (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1968; Accession 2015-M-001
  - L'Enseignement Revolutionaire: Organe Mensuel de Liason des CER, 1968 June (Box 1, Folder 1)